rockthevote.com 2019-05-11

# Privacy Policy - Rock the Vote

Effective and Last Updated: 27 June 2018

This website and associated tools, such as the voter registration platform,  is owned and operated by **Rock the Vote** (hereinafter “RTV”) and we have a firm commitment to your privacy and Internet privacy in general. We are committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors and users while they interact with the content and services on this site ([ **www.rockthevote.org**](https://www.rockthevote.org/) , the “Site”). This Privacy Policy applies to the Site and RTV owned services only.  It does not apply to other websites to which we may link. We do gather certain types of information about our users, so we want you to understand what information we collect about you, how we collect it, how that information is used, and how you can control our disclosure of it.  You agree that your use of the Site signifies your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use this Site.

  1. **Information Collected**

We collect two (2) types of information from you: 1) information that you voluntarily supply in form fields on this Site (e.g., through a voluntary registration process, or sign-up for email); and 2) information that may be derived through automated tracking mechanisms.

  1.  Voluntary Information for Services and Features

We collect personally identifiable information when you choose to use certain other features of the Site, including a) registering to vote, b) consenting to receive email or text messages about upcoming elections or events, c) consenting to receive email or text messages about advocacy actions or d) participating in any social media interaction as part of the Site.  When you choose to use these additional features, we may require you to provide your “Contact Information” in addition to other personal information that may be required to complete a transaction.

  2. Cookies

Our site uses “cookies” and other web tracking technologies. Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. If a user’s system is idle for a defined time, the cookie may expire, and if so, forcing the user to sign in again to continue their session. This prevents unauthorized access to the user’s information while they are away from their computer.

You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser, but please note that if you choose to erase or block your cookies, you may need to re-enter your original user ID and password to gain access to certain parts of the Site.

  2. **How We Use Your Information**

**rockthevote.org** only uses your personal information for the original purposes it was given. For example, all personal information and other unique identifiers submitted in the process of registering to vote are used to produce the voter registration form for you to send to your local or state election officials or to confirm the appropriate online submission form. If you provide a state-issued identification number or Social Security number, it will be used solely for the production of your voter registration form and will not be stored by RTV for more than two weeks past submission.  Understand that once you mail in or electronically submit your voter registration application to your local or state election officials, it becomes a matter of public record and is available for inspection and use by those who satisfy the requirements of the State law governing its use.

**rockthevote.org** will not sell any personal information to third parties.  Some information on our supporter lists, such as names, email addresses, and addresses, may be exchanged with named partners and other organizations with principles and/or missions that overlap with those of RTV. Supporters may opt out of such supporter list exchanges at any time. Our purpose is to protect your information while making sure you have what you need to make an informed decision on Election Day.

Please note that personally identifiable information is used only to provide you with a more enjoyable, convenient online experience and to help us identify and/or provide information that may be of interest to you. We use your personally identifiable information to support and enhance your use of the Site and its features, including without limitation: tracking email we send to you, and otherwise supporting your use of the Site.

We may permit certain trusted third parties to track usage, analyze data such as the source address that a page request is coming from, your IP address or domain name, the date and time of the page request, the referring Web site (if any) and other parameters in the URL. This is collected in order to better understand our Web site usage, and enhance the performance of services to maintain and operate the Site and certain features on the Site. We may use third parties to host the Site; operate various features available on the Site; send you email; analyze data; provide search results and links and assist in fulfilling your orders.

**rockthevote.org** may disclose Contact Information in special cases where we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our terms and conditions of use or may be causing injury or interference with our rights, property, our customers or anyone who could be harmed by such activities.

**We are not liable or responsible for personally identifiable or other information** **you choose to submit on any publicly accessible area of the Site.**

You will receive notice when your personally identifiable information might be provided to any third party for any reason other than as set forth in this Privacy Policy, and you will have an opportunity to request that we not share such information.

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design the Site and for business and administrative purposes. We may also use or share with third parties for any purpose aggregated data that contains no personally identifiable information.

  3. **How We Protect Your Information**

RTV is committed to protecting the information we receive from you. We take appropriate security measures to protect your information against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we maintain appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information and data stored on our system. While no computer system is ever completely secure, we believe the measures we have implemented reduce the likelihood of security problems to a level appropriate to the type of data involved. RTV permanently deletes the most sensitive user-submitted information, such as state ID or SSN numbers, two weeks after submission. Other personally identifying contact information is stored by RTV’s vendor, EveryAction, whose privacy policy can be found [here](https://www.everyaction.com/content/privacy-policy). In the case of a personal data breach, RTV will notify individuals about potential threats within 72 hours after having become aware it.

  4. **Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information and Preferences**

[We provide mechanisms for updating and correcting your personal information.](https://secure.everyaction.com/j0NIDGZK6E-iXx4_d32Uhg2) Your personal information and data are accessible across multiple platforms and devices of varying types, including smartphones, tablets, and computers. You may also access and update your profile information **and your preferences to receive email or other communications from us by sending an email to**[ **info@rockthevote.org**](mailto:info@rockthevote.org).

  5. **Email Choice/Opt-out**

If any user who receives an email from the Site would prefer not to receive such communications in the future, he or she can unsubscribe by following the instructions and link in the email.  In addition, you may send an email to [**info@rockthevote.org**](mailto:info@rockthevote.org). We will make commercially reasonable efforts to implement your opt-out requests promptly, but you may still receive communications from us for up to ten business days as we process your request. Individuals who wish to invoke their right to be forgotten will be able to do so. Upon their request, individuals will have their information removed from RTV and all partner data storage systems. 

  6. **Disclaimer to Security**

By consenting to the Privacy Policy, you consent that no data transmission over the Internet is completely secure. We cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you provide to us, and you transmit such information to us at your own risk.

  7. **Notification of Changes**

**rockthevote.org** reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion. If at some point in the future, there is a change to our Privacy Policy, unless we obtain your express consent, such change will only apply to information collected after the revised Privacy Policy took effect. Your continued use of the Site indicates your assent to the Privacy Policy as posted.

  8. **Contact Information**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact:

**David Pruter**

**Privacy** **Officer**

**Rock the Vote**

**1875 Connecticut Ave NW, 10th Floor**

**Washington DC, 20009**
